Guide to the Charles Barsotti Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
- Accession 2018-136
  - "Halls Dept Store Ads"; Hallmark correspondence pertaining to job positions, Hall's Store ad project files, correspondence, rough drawings, newspaper ads, 1963-1997 (Box 2878, Folder 21)
  - "Hammacher Schlemmer"; Hammacher Schlemmer catalog cover project files, 4 copies of the Hammacher Schlemmer Holiday Preview, correspondence, 2003 (Box 2878, Folder 22)
  - "Harpers"; Harper's magazine project files, correspondence, drawings, 1967-1970, 1975 (Box 2878, Folder 23)
  - "Hawker"; Raytheon Aircraft Company Hawker project files, original drawings, correspondence, ad and idea sheets, 2003 (Box 2878, Folder 24)
  - "Alfred Heineken Music Foundation"; Alfred Heineken Music Foundation project files, correspondence, rough and original drawings, 1995 (Box 2878, Folder 25)
  - "Helicon Nine"; Helicon Nine Editions In the Black/In the Red: Poems of Profit & Loss illustration project, correspondence, one original drawing, no date, 2008-2009 (Box 2878, Folder 26)
  - "Hershey"; Hershey's chocolate company project files, correspondence, rough and original drawings for "For the Love of Chocolate by Sue" campaign which did not work out, 1991, 1999 (Box 2878, Folder 27)
  - "Hertz"; Hertz truck leasing ad campaign project files, payment invoice, magazine pages with illustrations by Barsotti, 1972 (Box 2878, Folder 28)
  - "U.K.-Home Office"; Home Office British government website security project files, correspondence, rough and original drawings, website roughs with Barsotti illustrations, 2008 (Box 2878, Folder 29)
  - "InCity Mag"; InCity magazine project files, magazine pages with Barsotti illustrations, 1 copy of InCity magazine, correspondence, 1975, 1994-1995, 2003-2004 (Box 2878, Folder 30)
  - "Alex Isley"; Alexander Isley Design project files, correspondence, rough drawings and sample cartoons for various projects with Alex Isley, 1994-1995, 2003-2004 (Box 2878, Folder 31)
  - "Katja/U.K.-Germany Promerit"; Promerit, Germany project files through Katja Thielen, Together Design, London, correspondence, rough and original drawings, invoices, 2007 (Box 2878, Folder 32)
  - "National Post 2002"; National Post Business magazine project files, correspondence, rough and original drawings, invoices, 3 copies of 3 copies of National Business Post, 1999-2000 (Box 2878, Folder 33)
  - Boardroom Inc. project files for Bottomline and Tax Hotline newsletters, correspondence, rough and original drawings, issues of Bottomline and Tax Hotline newsletters with Barsotti illustrations, 1983-1993 (Box 2879, Folder 1-26)
  - Bottomline and Tax Hotline newsletters with Barsotti illustrations, 1994-1998 (Box 2880, Folder 1-10)
  - "The 3i Calendar 1987 with Original Cartoons by Charles Barsotti"; 3i 1987 oversize calendar with cover illustration and cartoons by Barsotti (Box 2881, Folder 1)
  - "3i 1997 Calendar"; 3i 1997 oversize calendar with cover illustration by Barsotti (Box 2881, Folder 2)
  - "The 2005 3i Calendar Celebrating 20 Years"; 3i 2005 20th anniversary calendar with cover illustration by Barsotti (Box 2881, Folder 3)
- Accession 2019-080
  Additional archival material relating to the work and drawings of Charles Barsotti from 1991-1994. The majority of the material within the collection consists of original sketches of the NiceDay pup and other characters he created for WH Smith Supplies, along with faxes mainly between Mark Steen and Charles Barsotti. The collection also included newspapers, the Creative Review, an Office Supplies Catalogue and an Annual Report 1993 that all contained the NiceDay pup drawings, transaction statements for Barsotti's pay, and faxes from Hieroglyphics Designs. The folder titles preceding a semicolon reflect Barsotti's original descriptions.
  - Photocopies of Original Drawings (2 folders), December 16-17, 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 1-2)
  - "The story of NiceDay by Michael Wolff"; Background to NiceDay Pup creation, undated (Box 3117, Folder 3)
  - Creative Review; Page 25 NiceDay Pup Newell and Sorrell, WH Smith and Michael Wolff, October 1992 (Box 3117, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of Original Drawings (5 folders), November-December 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 5-9)
  - Faxes between Barsotti and Mark Steen of Drawings, July 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 10)
  - "NiceDay Contracts and Negotiations", February 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 11)
  - "Working on Pup cartoons for NiceDay"; Letters and drawings for NiceDay Projects, August 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 12)
  - "More Pup Drawings for Catalog"; Letters and NiceDay Pup Drawings, September 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 13)
  - "Charley's Faxes to Mark Steen"; Faxes and Drawings between Charley and Mark Steen, October 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 14)
  - Faxes and Drawings between Charley and Mark Steen, November 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 15)
  - "CB & Mark Steen"; Faxes and Drawings between Charley Barsotti and Mark Steen, December 1991 (Box 3117, Folder 16)
  - Faxes, Drawing and Letters of NiceDay Launch, 1992-1993 (Box 3117, Folder 17)
  - "1992 Jan. Peep Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, January 1992 (Box 3117, Folder 18)
  - "1992 Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen over the year (Box 3117, Folder 19)
  - "March 1992 Pup Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark (Box 3117, Folder 20)
  - Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, April 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 1)
  - "NiceDay Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, May 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 2)
  - "Pup Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, June 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen/NiceDay Company, September 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 4)
  - "NiceDay Launch Including Pup Sketches"; NiceDay Launch speech/letter, faxes and sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, August 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 5)
  - "Pup Sketches"; Faxes and Sketches between Charley and Mark Steen, July 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 6)
  - "WH Smith NiceDay Financial"; Financial Statements between Charley and Carol Smith, September 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 7)
  - "Drawings NiceDay"; Letters, faxes, and drawings between Charley and NiceDay Company, December 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 8)
  - Letters, faxes, and sketches between Charley, Mark Steen and NiceDay Company, December 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 9)
  - Statement of Charley Barsotti and Lion Sketches, October 2, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 10)
  - "WH Smith Correspondence"; Newel and Sorrell letters to Charley and Launch Invitation, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 11)
  - Faxes between Charley and Sue Scorer, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 12)
  - "WH Smith Misc."; Misc. sketches, copies of magazine and faxes for NiceDay Company, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 13)
  - Pentagon group, Office Supplies Catalogue; Barsotti Drawings on bottom corner of each page, larger drawings separating categories, 1992-1993 (Box 3118, Folder 14)
  - "Video Drawings"; NiceDay Pup drawings for Video with FedEx Receipt, August 14, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 15)
  - Drawings of Pup and Bird for supplies with FedEx Receipt, July 2, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 16)
  - NiceDay Drawings with FedEx receipts, May 29 and June 9, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 17)
  - "Launch Invitation/Christmas Invitation"; Invitation drawings for NiceDay Launch and Christmas with FedEx Receipt, June 17, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 18)
  - "16 Drawings for Slides"; NiceDay Pup Drawings and FedEx Receipt, August 31, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 19)
  - "Christmas Card"; Christmas Drawing of NiceDay Pup, October 28, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 20)
  - "Lion-Perforator"; Lion Drawing with notes and FedEx Receipt, November 23, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 21)
  - Drawings of NiceDay Pup and Bird with FedEx Receipt, March 10-11, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 22)
  - "Safe Solve, Document Wallet"; NiceDay Pup and Bird Drawings and FedEx Receipt, March 4, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 23)
  - "Photocopies of Drawings"; Drawings of NiceDay Pup and Bird with FedEx Receipt, March 3, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 24)
  - "Mini Cassettes, Helicopter"; NiceDay Pup Drawings with FedEx Receipt, November 5, 1992 (Box 3118, Folder 25)
  - Lion and Dog Drawing for Wolff with FedEx Receipt, November 20, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 1)
  - Photocopies of Drawings (2 folders), February 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 2-3)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for Supplies with FedEx receipts (2 folders), March 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 4-5)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for Telephone and Elastic Bands with FedEx receipt, March 17, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of Drawing for Solvent Cleaner, February 14, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of Drawing for Waste Bags with FedEx receipt, February 18, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 8)
  - Photocopies of Drawings with FedEx receipts (4 folders), February 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 9-12)
  - Photocopies of Drawings, February 6, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 13)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for NiceDay Supplies with FedEx receipt, April 17, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 14)
  - Original Drawings, January 6, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 15)
  - Photocopies of Originals, January 10, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 16)
  - Original Drawings, January 8, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 17)
  - Photocopy Drawing of Bird, January 28, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 18)
  - Photocopies of Drawings (3 folders), January 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 19-21)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for Ogilvy & Mather Direct, and Wolff with FedEx Receipt, December 8, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 22)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for NiceDay Supplies with FedEx receipt (3 folders), May and June 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 23-25)
  - Photocopy of Drawing for NiceDay with FedEx receipt, May 1, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 26)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for NiceDay Supplies with FedEx receipt (2 folders), May 18-19, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 27-28)
  - Photocopies of Lettering for Pads with FedEx receipt, May 21, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 29)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for NiceDay Supplies and van with FedEx receipt (4 folders), April-May 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 30-33)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for posters with FedEx receipt, April 7, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 34)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for NiceDay Supplies with FedEx receipt, April 2, 1992 (Box 3119, Folder 35)
  - "Ten Drawings for WH Smith Employee Manual"; Photocopies of Drawings, January 27, 1993 (Box 3119, Folder 36)
  - "Catalog of Drawings"; Photocopies of Drawings with FedEx receipt, January 8, 1993 (Box 3119, Folder 37)
  - Photocopies of Drawings with notes, January 22, 1993 (Box 3119, Folder 38)
  - Photocopies of Drawings for envelopes with FedEx receipt, January 13, 1993 (Box 3119, Folder 39)
  - Sketches, letters and faxes between Charley and NiceDay Company (3 folders), January-September 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 40-42)
  - Newspaper featuring NiceDay, letters, faxes and sketches between Charley and WH Smith Business, October 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 43)
  - Statements, receipts, sketches and faxes between Charley and NiceDay, November-December 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 44)
  - "HPS"; Sketches, letter, faxes, newspaper articles and letter from HPS Marketing, 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 45)
  - "Hieroglyphics"; Letters and faxes from Hieroglyphics Design, 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 46)
  - Negative and Ads of supplies, Newspaper and sketches, 1994 (Box 3119, Folder 47)
  - Faxes, letters and sketches between Charley and Mark Steen and faxes from Hieroglyphics Design, January 1993 (Box 3119, Folder 48)
  - Letters, faxes, sketches and FedEx receipts between Charley Barsotti and Mark Steen, February 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 1)
  - Faxes, letters, sketches and statements between Charley, Mark Steen and WH Smith Business, March-April 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 2)
  - Letters, faxes and sketches between Charley and Mark Steen for NiceDay, May-June 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Faxes, Sketches and Receipts to and from Charley Barsotti, July-August 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 4)
  - Letters, Faxes, Sketches and Receipts to and from Charley Barsotti, September-October 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 5)
  - Faxes, Letters, Sketches, Statements and FedEx receipts to and from Charley Barsotti, November-December 1993 (Box 3120, Folder 6)
  - Original Sketch of cat for Office Environment by Barsotti, undated (Box 3120, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report 1993 WH Smith Group plc; Report manual with Barsotti's pup drawing on the corner of the pages and large drawing on page 22 (Box 3120, Folder 8)